Jorge Allan Paz Garza

Phone: +52 6621826450

Email: jallanpazg@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jorge-allan-paz-garza/

GitHub: https://github.com/Gokuno

Portfolio: https://allan-portafolio.vercel.app/

Professional Summary

Engineer with 10 years of experience in web development and programming. I have professional experience working with Wordpress, PHP, React, Vue.js and Next.js. Worked on building full stack secure, scalable, and performant web apps. Experienced in integrating front-end and back-end systems, creating database schemas, and deploying secure, efficient solutions.

Academic Background

- Mechatronics Engineering
 Universidad Tecnológica de Hermosillo, Son. Mexico
- Associate Degree in Electronics and Automation Universidad Tecnológica de Hermosillo, Son. Mexico

Additional Training

- CS50: Introduction to Programming with Python (In Progress)
- CS50: Introduction to Computer Science and Programming (In Progress)
- HTML5 and CSS3 from Basic to Advanced Udemy
- Master in JavaScript: Learn JS, JQuery, Angular, Node.js Udemy
- The Ultimate SEO Training 2023 + SEO for WordPress Websites Udemy
- Responsive Web Design Certification freeCodeCamp
- JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures Certification freeCodeCamp
- Al and Machine Learning (informal)

Skills

Technical Proficiency

- Languages: C++, Python, PHP, TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, SQL
- Frameworks & Libraries: Next.js, ReactJS, Vue.js, TailwindCSS, Prisma, Node.js, Laravel
- Database Management: PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB
- Cloud Platforms: AWS, GCP, Heroku

Languages: Advanced English (conversational, writing, reading) and Advance Spanish (conversational, writing, reading).

Professional Experience

Web Developer and Designer - 1UP Web Designs

Hermosillo, Son. | March 2020 - December 2024

- Developed and designed high-performance, secure web applications integrating using React, Vue.js and Next.js.
- Developed Wordpress websites optimized for performance and SEO.
- Optimized systems for accessibility, scalability, and security compliance.
- Deployed and managed relational databases (PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB and others) for multiple clients.

Web Designer/ Full stack Developer – External Consultant

Hermosillo, Son. | Since December 2014

- Designed responsive, scalable web solutions with a focus on integration between user-facing components and server-side systems.
- Implemented secure user authentication and authorization solutions for dynamic platforms.
- Project development for different clients in Mexico, USA and Canada.

Institutional Linkage Coordinator and Systems - Instituto Sonorense de Educación para el Adulto

Hermosillo, Son. | October 2015 - December 2019

- Established and managed agreements with government institutions and companies to provide educational services, overseeing the execution and follow-up of agreements.
- Worked on the ISEA web portal as well as the platform to take tests online.

Installation and Programming and Webmaster - IGATEK

Hermosillo, Son. | February 2010 - September 2015

- Participated in the creation of LED screens for businesses using LabVIEW and performed cleaning and installation of bird repellent systems on Telcel antennas.
- Programming PIC's for electronic devices and projects.
- Build the website and maintained it.

Project Supervisor - Proyectos y Obras Especializadas S.A. de C.V.

Hermosillo, Son. | February 2002 - September 2009

 Directed budgeting, administration, and supervision of projects with an emphasis on earthworks and leveling.

Featured Projects

Real-Time Slack Clone

- Built a real-time messaging platform using Next.js, ReactJS, MongoDB, and Convex.
- Features include secure user authentication, role-based permissions, and scalable backend architecture.

Airbnb Clone

 Created a full-stack platform for property rentals with features such as secure booking and user management using Next.js and Prisma.

Project Management App

• Developed a project management app that allows teams to share updates and comments using Next.js in the frontend and Postgresql at the backend.